Guide to the Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union, Local 1-S, Records WAG.012
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union (RWDSU), Local 1-S, Records
1939-2023, ongoing
1947-1976
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union. Local 1-S Department Store Workers Union (New York, N.Y.)
WAG.012
13 Linear Feet in 13 record cartons.
4 websites in 4 archived websites.
Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union, Local 1-S Department Store Workers Union was organized at Macy's in New York City on June 7, 1939 by the Congress of Industrial Organizations' Department Store Organizing Committee. Headed by Sam Kovenetsky, a stockroom worker who served as Business Manager of Local 1-S from 1939 to 1948 and as President from 1948 to 1980, the union bargained for employee benefits including increased job security, higher minimum wages, and a company-paid health insurance plan. Originally affiliated with the Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Union (RWDSU), Local 1-S and other left-wing locals seceded from the RWDSU in 1948 after the passage of the Taft-Hartley Act. However, in 1951 Local 1-S re-affiliated with the CIO under a separate charter as an international union, the United Department Store Workers of America and in 1955 the Local re-affiliated with the RWDSU. The records consist of correspondence, minutes, constitutions, notes, speeches, newsletters, agreements, contract negotiations, grievances, annual reports, economic reports, memoranda, circulars and brochures.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by the Local 1-S Department Store Workers Union in three donations from 1979 to 1981. The accession number associated with this gift is 1979.016.
Websites were initially selected by curators and captured through the use of The California Digital Library's Web Archiving Service in 2007 as part of the Labor Unions and Organizations (U.S.) Web Archive. In 2015, these websites were migrated to Archive-It. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website. In circa 2015, the original URL associated with this collection, http://www.local1srwdsu.org/, became defunct. In 2018, the new URL, https://www.1srwdsu.org/, was added to the web archive. The accession number associated with this website is 2019.094. In July 2021, https://local1s.nationbuilder.com/ was added to the web archive. The accession number associated with this website is 2022.009. In August 2023, https://rwdsulocal1s.org/ was added. The accession number associated with this website is 2023.068.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Historical Note
The Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union, Local 1-S Department Store Workers Union had its origins in efforts to organize the workers of Macy's department store in New York City. These efforts came to fruition with the passage of the Wagner Act in 1935 and the establishment of the Congress of Industrial Organizations (CIO) in 1938. The CIO's Department Store Organizing Committee, headed by Samuel Wolchok, began to focus on the large department stores in New York City and chose Sam Kovenetsky, a stockroom worker, to head the organizing drive at Macy's. Kovenetsky served as Business Manager of Local 1-S from 1939 to 1948, and President from 1948 to 1980.
First organized on June 7, 1939, Local 1-S was at first confined to non-selling departments of Macy's, but by 1943, 54% of the salesclerks voted for union representation. Through negotiations, Local 1-S bargained for employee benefits including increased job security, higher minimum wages, and a company-paid health insurance plan. Contracts banning racial, religious and gender discrimination were also achieved.
From its inception as an affiliate of the Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Union (RWDSU), the left-wing leadership of Local 1-S clashed with Samuel Wolchok, then head of the international union and a right-wing Socialist. Although achieving a period of uneasy cooperation during World War II, Local 1-S and other left-wing unions seceded en masse in 1948 after the RWDSU's endorsement of the Taft-Hartley Act's non-Communist affidavit provision.
However, in 1951 Local 1-S re-affiliated with the CIO under a separate charter as an international, the United Department Store Workers of America. In 1955, the year of the AFL-CIO merger, Local 1-S re-affiliated with the RWDSU. A 13-day strike against Macy's in 1956 won improvements in job security and wage rates. In 1963 the union achieved a 37 ½ hour work week for its members, and the late 60s saw significant advances in benefits. The Local, long active in New York civil rights activities was well represented at the 1963 March on Washington.
Local president Sam Kovenetsky, a well-known figure in New York trade-union circles, served as a vice-president of the RWDSU and of the New York State AFL-CIO. He chaired the New York City Central Labor Council's Camp Committee, and sat on the Executive Board of the Maritime Trades Department, AFL-CIO. He also attended international meetings of representatives of department-store unions and other white-collar unions and was an advisor on industrial education to the New York City Board of Education.
By 1980, when President Kovenetsky retired, Local 1-S was the nation's largest department-store union. Kovenetsky was succeeded by Local vice-president Joe Pascarella. The Local currently represents over 3,500 active employees at Macy's flagship Herald Square store in Manhattan and workers at the Queens, Parkchester and White Plains stores.
Sources:
"1-S, Twenty-five Years of Progress, 1938-1963." Local 1-S, Anniversary Pamphlet, 1964.
Kirstein, George G. Stores and Unions. New York: Fairchild Press, 1950.
Opler, Daniel. For All White-Collar Workers: The Possibilities of Radicalism in New York's Department Store Workers, 1934-1953. Athens, OH: Ohio University Press, 2007.
Scope and Content Note
Series I: Constitutions, By-laws and Minutes, 1939-1979, contains printed booklets of the Local's constitution and by-laws, as well as minutes of Executive Board and General Membership meetings. Some of the early minutes of the Executive Board are in bound minute-books.
Series II: General and Macy's Herald Square Files, 1939-1997, contains administrative materials and files concerning the day-to-day activities of the union at its primary shop. Arbitration, negotiation and membership information are included, as are subject files, circulars, correspondence and agreements. Files relating to union committees, such as the Committee on Political Education, the Negotiations Committee and the Trial Committee are present. Of particular significance are files of material produced by Macy's, including annual reports, employee handbooks and circulars, an in-house newspaper and publicity materials.
Series III: Other Shop Files, 1944-1972, consists of organizing materials and related information pertaining to other shops of Local 1-S, including Macy's locations in Brooklyn, Queens and the Bronx, as well Macy's divisions, such as Suburban Food and Bamberger's. The most substantial documentation is for Macy's Roosevelt Field and Suburban Foods shops.
Series IV: Sam Kovenetsky Files, 1943-1979, contains correspondence between Kovenetsky and union members, Macy's executives and other unions, as well as speeches, notes and biographical information. Material relating to his involvement in other organizations, including the Greater New York Fund, Group Health Insurance, Labor for Carey Committee and the Workmen's Circle Home and Infirmary for the Aged is also included.
Series V: Legal Counsel Files, 1947-1974, contain records from the office of O'Donnell and Schwartz, Local 1-S' legal firm. The majority of the files pertain to arbitration matters and contract negotiations.
Arrangement
Folders are arranged alphabetically.
The files are organized into six series:
Series I: Constitutions, By-Laws and Minutes, 1939-1979
Series II: General and Macy's Herald Square Files, 1939-1997
Series III: Other Shop Files, 1944-1972
Series IV: Sam Kovenetsky Papers, 1943-1979
Series V: Legal Counsel Files, 1947-1974
Series VI: Archived Websites, March 2009-ongoing
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
The following collections contain materials related to the RWDSU:
Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union, Local 3, United Store Workers (WAG 230)
Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union, Local 3, United Store Workers Photographs (PHOTOS 186)
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Moving Images Collection (FILMS 001)
United Automobile Workers of America, District 65 Oral History Collection (OH 019)
United Automobile Workers of America, District 65 Photographs (PHOTOS 023)
Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union, Local 1-S Department Store Workers Union Photographs (PHOTOS 028)
United Automobile Workers of America, District 65 Records (WAG 006).
Take Down Policy
Archived websites are made accessible for purposes of education and research. NYU Libraries have given attribution to rights holders when possible; however, due to the nature of archival collections, we are not always able to identify this information.
If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials.
If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to the repository email.
Please include the following in your notice: Identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature. Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice.
Clippings (information artifacts); Pamphlets.; Newsletters.; New York (N.Y.).; Labor unions -- Organizing -- United States.; Minutes (administrative records); Circulars (fliers); Strikes and lockouts -- Retail trade -- New York (State) -- New York; Correspondence.; Constitutions.; Contracts; Collective labor agreements.; Department stores -- Employees -- Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York; Department stores -- Employees -- New York (State) -- New York.; Retail trade; Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union. Local 1-S Department Store Workers Union (New York, N.Y.); Kovenetsky, Sam; Macy's (Firm); Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union. Local 1-S Department Store Workers Union (New York, N.Y.)
- Series I: Constitutions, By-Laws and Minutes, 1939-1979
  - Constitution and By-Laws, 1947-1949, 1968, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Minutes: Executive Board, Jul 1939-Sep 1941 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Minutes: Executive Board, Oct 1941-Jul 1943 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Minutes: Executive Board, Nov 1943-Dec 1943 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Minutes: Executive Board, Apr 1945-Mar 1946 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Minutes: Executive Board, Apr 1946-May 1948 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Minutes: Executive Board, Jun 1948-Feb 1949 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Minutes: Executive Board, 1955-1965 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Minutes: Executive Board, 1966-1969 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Minutes: Executive Board, 1970-1975 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Minutes: General Membership Meeting, 1948, 1957, 1961-1963 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Minutes and Attendance Reports: General Membership Meeting, 1965-1966, 1971-1973, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Series II: General and Macy's Herald Square Files, 1939-1997
  - Agreements, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Agreements, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Agreements, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Agreements, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Agreements, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Agreements, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Agreements, 1947-1951 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Agreements, 1953-1965, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Agreements, 1970-1976, 1978-1980 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - American Parkinson Disease Association: David Siegal Dinner, May 1973 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Anti-Discrimination Committee, 1946-1950 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Anti-Discrimination Committee, 1951-1953 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Arbitrations, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Arbitrations, 1946-1948 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Arbitrations (I), 1952 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Arbitrations (II), 1952 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Arbitrations (III), 1952 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Arbitrations (IV), 1952 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Arbitrations (V), 1952 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Arbitrations (I), 1955 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Arbitrations (II), 1955 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Arbitrations (III), 1955 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Arbitrations (IV), 1955 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Arbitrations, 1962, 1965, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Assessment Trials, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Benefits: Health, 1957-1970 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Benefits: Health, 1971-1978 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Benefits: Pension Plan, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Benefits: Pension Plan, 1965-1975 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Blue Laws, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Brown, Harry v. Local 1-S, United Department Store Workers(Equal Employment Opportunity case), 1973 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Clippings, 1946-1956 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Clippings, 1964-1966, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Committee on Political Education, 1955-1964 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Committee on Political Education: Correspondence, 1955-1963 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Conference: Agenda and Clippings, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Congress of Industrial Organizations Department Store Employees Organizing Committee, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Constitution Committee, 1959-1974 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Contracts: Other Locals, 1942, 1950-1973 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Contracts: Other Unions, 1969-1971 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Convention (International Union), 1962, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence: Policies, 1945-1956 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Policies, 1957-1967 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Policies, 1968-1971 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Policies, 1972-1974 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Policies, 1975-1979 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Policies - Index, 1945-1979 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Curley, Walter J. v. Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Workers, Local 1-S (New York State Supreme Court): Summons and Motion, 1948-1950 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Department Store Workers, Local 1000 (Toronto): Organizing, 1950-1953 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Department Store Workers, Local 1000 (Toronto): Unionize(Shop Paper), 1951-1953 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Divisional Meetings: Agendas, Notes and Reports, 1946-1948, 1960-1967 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Divisional Meetings: Attendance Reports, 1973, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Elections and Objections Committee, 1962-1965 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Elections: Circulars, 1949, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Elections: Vote Tally, Jan 1963 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Executive Board: Correspondence, 1946-1948, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Executive Board: Members, Mar 1, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Executive Board: Notes, 1946-1948 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Finances, 1947-1977 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - General Electric Strike, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Grievances, 1959-1966 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Grievances, 1967-1973 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Grievances, 1975-1978 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Hawaii Trip, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - History, 1939-1949, 1979, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - "Just Organize" (poem), 1973 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Keyserling, Leon H.: "The Employees of Macy's Deserve Large Pay Increases Now" (typescript), Mar 1968 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - King-Anderson Bill (health care for the elderly), 1963 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Kovenetsky, Sam: Correspondence to Shop Stewards, 1949-1956 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Kovenetsky, Sam: Testimonial Dinner and Dance, Sep 1973 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Legislation, 1974-1977 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Legislation: New York Legislative Service, 1972-1976 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Local 1-S Federal Credit Union, 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - "Local 1-S Is Your Union" (pamphlet), 1956, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Local 1-S Newsletter, Apr 1960-May 1960 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - "The Local 1-S Story" (film proposal), 1963 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Local 1-S Realty Corporation: Finances, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Macy Star, 1946-1950, 1975-1977 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Macy's: Annual Reports, 1955-1962 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Macy's: Annual Reports, 1969-1973 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Macy's: Employee Memoranda, 1945-1977 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Macy's: Economic Reports, 1938, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Macy's: Employee Circulars, 1948-1949 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Macy's: Employee Handbooks, 1952-1961 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Macy's: History, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Macy's: Organizational Chart, Aug 1, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Macy's: Other Branches, 1963-1966 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Macy's: Program for 49th Annual Banquet Honoring Mr. Jack I. Straus, May 6, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Macy's: Publicity, 1952-1972 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Membership, 1947-1973 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Membership: Cards and Credential, 1941-1979 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Membership: Correspondence, 1971-1977 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Membership: Dues, 1947-1971 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Membership: New Membership Classes, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Metro Labor Press Council, 1976-1977 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Metro Labor Press Council, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - National War Labor Board, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Negotiations, 1944-1946 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Negotiations, 1947-1948 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Negotiations, 1950-1954 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Negotiations, 1955-1956 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Negotiations, 1958-1959 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Negotiations (I), 1961 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Negotiations (II), 1961 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Negotiations, 1962-1963 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Negotiations, 1964-1965 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Negotiations, 1968-1971 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Negotiations, 1972-1973 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Negotiations, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Negotiations: Circulars, 1944-1948 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Negotiations: Circulars, 1949-1954 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Negotiations: Circulars, 1962-1980 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Negotiations Committee: Minutes, 1961-1963 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Negotiations Committee: Minutes, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - New York City Central Labor Council: Summer Camp Program, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - New York State Department of Labor: Brochures, 1967-1976 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Office Inventory, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Organizational Charts, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Political Action Committee, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Political Action Committee: Circulars, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Political Action Committee: Correspondence, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Press Releases, 1948-1972 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - "Punchout" (play): Script, Press Releases, Dec 1980 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Retail Clerks International Union, undated (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Workers Union and Local 1-S Split (Communist issue), 1946-1949 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Workers Union and Local 1-S Split (Communist issue): Flyers, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Scholarships, 1961-1962 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Scholarships, 1965-1966 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Scholarships, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Scholarships, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Scholarships, 1969-1970 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Scholarships, 1972-1973 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Scholarships, 1974-1975 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Scholarships, 1976-1977 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Scholarships, 1978-1979 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Shop Stewards and Executive Committee Meetings, 1948, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Shop Stewards: Bulletins, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Shop Stewards Conference, 1951-1952, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Shop Stewards Conference, 1963-1968 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Shop Stewards Conference, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Shop Stewards Conference, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Shop Stewards Conference, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Shop Stewards Conference, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Shop Stewards Conference, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Shop Stewards Conference, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Shop Stewards Conference, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Shop Stewards Handbook, 1949-1962 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Shop Stewards Logs, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Shop Stewards Meetings, 1952, 1969-1974 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Shop Stewards Newsletters, 1949-1952 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Shop Stewards: Training, 1964, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Sobol, Norman L. (Editor): Correspondence, 1959-1974 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Social Events: Circulars, 1944-1950 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Staff Meetings, Apr 23, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Staff Meetings, 1961-1970 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Staff Meetings, 1971-1972 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Staff Meetings, 1973-1974 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Staff Training, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - "State of the Union" (President's Report), 1949, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Strike, 1948, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Strike, 1956-1968 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Strike, 1970-1974 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Strike: Placards, 1979 (Flat-file-folder 2)
  - Trial Committee, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Trial Committee, 1947-1948 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Trial Committee, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Trial Committee (I), 1953 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Trial Committee (II), 1953 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Trial Committee, 1954-1955 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Trial Committee, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Trial Committee, 1957-1958 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Trial Committee, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Trial Committee (I), 1960 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Trial Committee (II), 1960 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Trial Committee, 1962-1964 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Trial Committee, 1964-1971 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - "Twenty Five Years of Progress" (25th Anniversary Celebration): Program, May 23, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - United Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Employees of America, Local 3: Agreement, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - United States House of Representatives, Special Subcommittee on Education and Labor: Investigation of Communism in New York City Distributive Trades, Jul 1, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Wage and Contractual Changes, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Wage and Contractual Changes, 1962-1968 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Wage and Contractual Changes, 1969-1970 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Wage and Contractual Changes, 1971-1972 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Wage and Contractual Changes, 1973-1974 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Wage and Contractual Changes, 1975-1976 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Wage and Contractual Changes, 1977-1978 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Wages: Contested Promotion and Open to Hire Lists, 1960-1968 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Wages: Minimum Wage Rates, 1939-1971 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Wages: Pro Rates, 1954-1955 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Wages: Pro Rates, 1958-1959 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Wages: Pro Rates, 1960-1961 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Wages: Pro Rates (I), 1964-1965 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Wages: Pro Rates (II), 1964-1965 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Wages: Pro Rates, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 11)